We're back at Mack Signs Designs.
We're doing another wrap on another car.
[upbeat music]
So before we did a wrap, this
is technically PPF,
and the difference is-
This is going to protect your car as well
as give it that look you're after
So traded in the RS6, got an Audi RSQ8.
This is going to be my Mrs's car.
It's not that I don't trust her driving,
it's
just that I want to protect the paint from
the outside world.
And on the RS6,
someone reversed into the wheel arch,
and the PPF
completely prevented any damage happening
to the car.
So we're going with potentially a stealth
PPF.
And because this is the business channel,
we're going to be talking business.
I want to know cost, markups, profits,
business opportunity.
Mainly because I find this super
interesting and I'm working backwards.
I think this could be one of the easiest
products and services
to market in the world,
which gets me excited because first of
all, on cars, if you
damage a panel and it needs to be
repainted, getting
that paint to match other
panels can be very complex
and very expensive.
Second of all,
it's just classic loss aversion.
When you do insurance,
you get protected against all the things
you're worried
about, even like fire and theft, which
is statistically hugely unlikely.
So it's like an insurance policy you can
put on your car, and it makes it look
sick.
Because if you come here from this angle,
you notice that we go from a gloss.
Would you call this satin, Mack?
Yeah, satin. So it's a semi-gloss.
Which just makes it look like the
Batmobile under the guise of doing it for
protection.
And there's another thing I saw,
I can't remember what it was, but
someone was saying, if you want a new car,
go get your car washed.
Because most people,
once they get their car washed,
have a brand new
relationship to their car.
They like it more.
But again,
I would say one level further to that
is if you get your car wrapped, it
makes you feel like you've got a new car.
That's how I felt after the Porsche.
So this is a way less expensive means of
customizing a car.
And if you put branding on this,
tax deductible because it becomes
advertising.
Is that right?
Might put a snakey sticker on there
somewhere.
Yeah.
It doesn't even have to be massive because
if the tax authority, whether ATO
or HMRC, come knocking, you go, "Oh, no,
the sole purpose of this wasn't to protect
the car, it was to promote the business."
That's right. As always.
Thank you very much, ATO, HMRC.
[chuckles]
This stuff is pretty expensive.
Yeah, it is.
You can pretty much double any sort of
vehicle wrap.
This is a protective film,
so it's completely different.
Different technologies to any sort of
standard wrap.
It'll prevent stone chips,
scratch-resistant, self-healing.
It's pretty-
The self-healing thing.
Yeah, it's pretty incredible.
So if there's a small scratch on
that in the sunlight-
It'll heal it. It'll come back together.
So if you scratch that with,
you rub up against it with a handbag
or something like
that, you sit it out in the sun for a day,
and it'll be gone the next day.
The reason I love this as well from a
marketing perspective is there's loads of
viral videos online where people have a
panel of a car, they get their keys, they
scratch the panel and the PPF,
then they get a brick,
and they rub it across.
Mm.
Then they peel the PPF off,
and you can see that the paintwork
underneath is
unaffected.
Do you want to do it?
No. [both laughing] No.
So from a marketing perspective,
I've already said this, I
don't mind if people know.
The second I see PPF, I said to Mack,
I go, "Okay,
here's a business idea.
Whichever panel someone gets damaged on
their car, you
bring it back,
we'll fix it for free." I say we,
this isn't my business, not yet.
As long as you can make social media
content showing how well it worked.
Because if you fix someone's panel for
free, how much would
that cost in material,
do you reckon, and labor?
You'd have to be charging nearly $1,000,
I reckon.
So if you were to eat
that $1,000 cost yourself-
Yeah
...
if you were to do the labor for free
and just the print out of the PPF, what
are you looking at? A few hundred dollars?
Yeah.
So then you could say to yourself, "Right,
we're going to lose a few hundred
dollars as a business," which
is going to be just a generalized business
cost.
And out of that,
we're going to have some marketing
material that could potentially
go viral.
That's right.
And I think that in a business,
if you can eat some costs in some places
for
marketing, that one video showcasing,
even this video in some respects, the
benefits of having
that PPF could get a customer in the door.
And if you acquire one new customer from
that video that you did for free and lost
$400, you could be profitable. Even
if you were to only break even from
that new customer,
do they then get another car wrap?
Do they then refer another friend in?
Do they then give you a social media post
with their transformative process?
That's the way my brain works with it all.
That looks cool.
And you say you got a glossy one?
We've got a glossy one too, yeah.
So you won't get any of the imperfections
in the paintwork. Brand-new car,
just from sitting outside in the salty air
and
just the sun and the rain and all
that sort of stuff, you start to get
imperfections, especially in black.
Black's wild.
So Mack had to buy the print of the car of
this
model for $1,000?
Yeah. So the templates for this RSQ8,
this latest model.
So we've bought the package,
the template package,
for every single little panel on
this car so that we can run it through our
machine, our cutting machine, to cut out
the shapes of the car on the film.
That's class.
So then you'd use a lot less material,
and then it becomes more of a
jigsaw-
That's right, yeah
... than it does with the Porsche,
having to wrap that rear bumper,
front panels.
Yeah.
We had those square sheets,
and you're having to fit them on, cut.
It's quite a lot of wasted material.
Yeah. It's just a different process.
They're two totally different separate
processes.
And this doesn't have as much stretch as a
wrap.
No. It is wrappable,
but it doesn't stretch that well.
It really needs to be cut to the shape of
the car to mold into the sections.
This looks amazing. You see the gloss
that comes into this matte?
Yeah.
It's starting to really come to life.
And I know there's a double effect here
where some dealerships in the
UK with the Adamas,
they're very hesitant to see a car with a
wrap because they
think it might be covering bad paintwork.
Mm.
But then on the other flip side,
knowing that a car's got PPF on it-
It's a clear wrap.
You can see anything underneath it.
Amazing.
So this is our little test piece anyway,
just so James can see what his car's going
to look like. Pretty cool.
See where the money's going.
This to me just looks like such an
exciting business prospect because
like I say,
everything really boils down to marketing.
If you have something that's easy to
market, you have a good business.
And then the transaction for this,
if you don't mind people knowing, this is
$14,000-
Yep
... for the wrap. Say it proudly.
$14,000.
So about £7,000, which sounds insane.
Materials?
Yeah, this would be, materials
are about 4,000.
And then the template was 1,000.
Yep.
So already £2,500,
$5,000 gone just in materials
and the software or the template.
Yeah.
We're not even looking at labor,
and this is going to take a few days.
Yeah, that's right.
It'll take a couple of days.
Probably three days I'll spend on it,
and then we'll let it dry out.
We'll just let it sit there inside the
shop, just to keep an eye on any edging,
anything lifting, anything like that.
We'll heat it up, we'll warm it up,
let it sit,
and then it'll be out on the road.
And the beautiful thing about this
is being a promotional asset for the
business,
for New Tonic,
and we'll show you some of the branding
towards the end of the video
that we're going to put on it.
This means that I can use this,
put it into all my
expenses that are legitimate for the
business,
and reduce my profitability for the
year. Which means that
if you're doing it as a business for the
business, it's
going to work out considerably more
efficient than if you
were to do it out of your
own pocket.
Yeah.
That looks unreal.
It's cool, hey.
I'm excited for that.
Peel this off now?
Yeah, the sound is going to be
People will be like, "Ugh."
[laughs] What is that?
You know what, Declan?
Have a look at this.
When we came,
if you look at the screen inside,
you'll notice there's loads of
fingerprints on it,
so I even brought with me... Where is it?
Stand there.
Oh, it smells good in there, doesn't it?
So I even got some of the glass stick-on
laminate that you put there to stop
getting fingerprints,
but I didn't trust myself doing
that because you know when
you stick something on like a phone case?
Like a phone case.
Yeah. So I was like,
"We're going to leave
that for later on as well."
Yeah. It's my turn.
Yeah.
You stick it on. Down to me.
Now that I know how good you
are with those kind of parts,
I won't touch it.
As a man,
there are things you like to do yourself,
like change your number plates
and whatnot.
[laughs]
But now I'm like,
"I'll just come see Mac."
Come to me.
Now, I wonder if that is heat or if it's-
Yeah, I'm not sure
... paint stresses me out.
Yeah, paint's crazy, isn't it?
When I was young,
I never thought paint was an issue or
imperfections.
I never cared about stone chips when I
was 17, 18.
Yeah.
Granted, I was driving a Fiat Punto.
Little bit different.
Yeah, I think now with buying nice cars,
the first thing you stress about is the
exterior.
It's got to look perfect.
Mm.
But yeah, you speak to any detailer,
any car that's been
delivered from a factory
or from a dealership,
a lot of the time they need to go
get paint corrected because they come with
swirl marks, they come with all sorts of
imperfections in the paintwork.
So when it comes to wrapping a car,
so you're from a signage background.
Yeah.
Did you have to self-teach yourself?
I've been doing it for a long time,
so it's part of the, I guess, signage
background becomes a wrapping background.
Now I've worked in race car background,
so go to site and wrap all the race
cars for Australian teams
and things like that.
So it was sort of,
I just learnt along the way.
I've been doing it for 20 plus years now,
so it's kind of-
What excites me about this,
and I'll be honest,
is let's say we start a wrap shop.
I'm in charge of the marketing,
you're in charge of the wrapping.
Yeah.
You have to hire someone.
Declan would raid him for his friends
and a young
hardworking friend.
Yeah, let's go.
You teach them how to wrap.
It's not a skill
that they can just run away with
because the marketing, I think,
is the hardest component.
So for instance,
if you're a personal trainer
and a lot of PTs think that they,
"Okay, I'm going to be a PT,
then we're going to hire PTs."
Yeah.
Well, to hire a PT,
you need to take a percentage of their
income.
They're only going to work so much
and so long before they go,
"Fuck this guy"-
Yeah
... and do their own thing.
Yeah.
No personal trainer's going to let you
have the revenue because they can just go
on
the same gym floor, get the same clients,
do the same thing.
But if you're in a wrap shop
and someone trains you how to wrap a car,
you're still
dependent on them to bring you business.
Yeah.
Otherwise,
you just have a skill that's pretty
useless on its own.
Well, a lot of people do this job.
There's plenty of wrap shops around.
It's just being different
and standing out.
And likable.
And likable. Yeah,
you've got to be approachable.
We get a lot of customers come into this
shop, our sign shop, and they come to us
because they can approach us
and talk to us.
They can get a relationship with us.
[laughs] I came in and I was like,
"I think I need to wrap another car."
Yeah.
Where's your little deck of all the
different colors?
Yeah, I'll go grab it.
So because we train jujitsu literally just
opposite, every time I have an idea, I
come in. He's like, "Mate,
I'm working." I've got another idea about
potentially
starting a nursery.
Yeah.
Not me,
but I heard there's a wait list in the
local area. It smells like business.
[laughs]
This is cool. So our chrome.
Might be left to the golf in the chrome.
Oh, that's nice.
That's crazy.
Is that psychedelics?
Why not?
That's quite a cool. Well, actually,
all these colors are nice.
And these are all wraps.
Are some of these PPFs on there?
No, these are all wraps.
We can get colored PPFs.
Yeah, I've heard about it. Is
that crazy expensive?
Yeah, it's quite a lot more.
Where's the one I was looking at?
The military green.
Yeah, it's there.
Oh, this.
I was potentially looking at doing the
Audi RS6 in this.
It would be, but I think after a
while you might look at it
and become a bit
disenfranchised with it. But actually,
all of these are so cool.
I think that matches pretty much the paint
I've almost got, but blue.
That's sick. Yeah.
A little glittery because this
is glittery in the sun.
That's wild, isn't it?
Is that what you're getting, the glitter?
No, ours is going to be more of a matte.
Oh, mate. That,
it would be good on a Ventor SVJ or et
cetera. Not sure on the pink. These
are quite cool. Matte blacks.
Oh, dead matte black. Is
that so no reflections?
That's real deep, yeah.
That one there too. Deep black.
Shadow black. The carbon fiber wrap,
I have mixed feelings about this.
Yeah. I'm not too sure about it.
Some parts look cool as fuck. This
is the carbon fiber, but I think
that would just be
potentially too much.
I just feel like when I see carbon fiber,
if you don't know what real carbon fiber
looks like, that's fine.
Mm. True.
But when you've seen real carbon fiber
and then you put that up against it.
So this is what we're getting,
the satin black, but PPF, not wrap.
The best thing about your satin black,
though, you're going to see the metallic
coming through it.
Mm.
So when it's out in the sun,
you'll see that metallic.
This is just so exciting.
I think once you put this in front of
people-
Clear PPF
... clear carbon fiber.
Yeah, so you can put
that on a black background.
And make it go-
Make it look like carbon fiber.
See,
you know when you go into Porsche,
they have all the color placards on the
wall-
Yeah
... and all the different things?
There almost needs to be like a-
You can. We can get it.
We can get placards.
Do you know what we did there before with
that film?
Yeah.
I saw Matt Watson do it in one of his
videos, and again,
my marketing brain went,
"This is genius." Someone could inquire
online and you go, "What colors are you
interested in?" They go, "Oh,
I'm interested in
matte red." You then say, "Right, cool.
For this person coming in 11:30,
let's get a little square made." Go up to
the car,
ba, ba, bum, bum.
Put it up.
This is what it's going to look like.
It's going to cost about $14,000.
We can invoice you however you want it.
We recommend that maybe you do put a
little company logo on it for your
business so
that you don't have a tough time with the
ATO.
It's going to take roughly four days.
If you live further out in Sydney,
we can send a driver to collect the car.
Yeah. We can even pick it up on transport.
Cool.
Yeah.
Do you like that or do you want to look at
some other colors? I like that, cool.
We'll book you in for the 27th.
How you get?
[laughs] See you soon.
What panel do you think you're going to
start with?
We'll probably do the bonnet.
Okay.
So the bonnet will be the biggest piece to
get out of the way.
Yeah, it's one of those things,
I'll prep this whole car.
We're going to have to prep it,
get rid of any rain spots
or anything like that,
any contaminants.
We're going to have to go over the whole
car, all the edges,
everything like that.
Because what we're going to do
is pop the bonnet, wrap around
the bonnet, so it'll wrap around about 10,
15 mil.
With the one I have in the RS6,
I could literally feel the line the whole
way
around.
Yeah.
And when I first started talking to you,
I assumed someone with a scalpel must have
gone round, but it felt too perfect.
Yeah. It's probably machine cut.
And I thought,
unless it's the flipping guy for
Rolls-Royce that paints the lines.
Yeah. [laughs] Yeah.
That does it by hand, I was like, "No,
it just doesn't make sense." Yeah,
you could
see some of the bits, but yeah,
I'm buzzing to see how it looks like
underneath.
Yeah.
It's going to be a completely new car.
Yeah, it'll look different.
The self-healing thing's crazy.
I never knew that.
As far as wheels,
is there any technology
or anything where you can protect wheels
with something like that?
Doubt it, no.
And it's not really going to do much.
If you've got a two-ton vehicle that hits-
Yeah
... a curb even at five miles an hour,
it's just-
No, you just don't do it.
Mm.
Even as someone who I'd say
is a decorated driver, I've been parking
about a foot away from every curb with
this.
I'd rather be sticking out in the road
than going too close.
Come have a look at this, Declan.
Come real close if you want.
These doors don't need to be slammed.
That's rad. I love that
I bought this car without test driving it,
which was brave.
There's no frames around the-
Yeah, it's all pillarless
... doors.
Yeah.
Which is quite nice.
It's quite brave.
And I'm changing the steering wheel.
This is where Dickhead James comes out.
He's becoming more prevalent.
We've had a good year.
This steering wheel just feels a little
bit too cheap, and
alcantara is what I want.
When I came to look at the car, it
was the one thing I
wanted to change.
That should come in a few weeks.
We can change that over.
Happy days.
Just want to feel a bit of suede.
I want this in my hands
when we're driving.
The first thing I do as well
when I get a car
is I always have to have a hands-free
phone holder.
That's literally the day the car comes,
I buy three or four of them from Amazon
and
I put the best one. Because in Australia,
if you want to change songs, as long as
there's a factory-mounted phone holder,
fine.
The second that comes into your hands,
game over people. Be smart.
Get one of these. You can get them
that clip into your air vents as well.
Do you have one of these?
Yeah.
They're good.
Don't leave the house without one.
You need them.
Yeah, 100%. That's about it. This thing
is the thirstiest car I've ever had
as far as drinking petrol, but
that you can't put through the business.
Smiles per miles is the equation you
should be looking at.
For any of you mathematicians out there,
how many smiles am I accruing per miles
that I'm driving?
So we're going to make a wrap shop purely
out of fun.
It might not even make any money,
but we'll get to have pleasurable
transmit.
Well, this actually... Right.
I had some plumbers come around my house
the
other day to fit a home filtration system.
Oh, nice.
To filter my water for the showers.
Like Kian's got eczema.
Complete home filtration.
They look after it anywhere in Australia.
So they fit a box by my mains water,
which has got three filters in it, and it
filters all the water coming into the
house, so for showers-
Yeah, nice
... baths, everything like that. Now,
I currently do filter my tap water with a
filter called a Zero filter.
Yeah.
A ZeroWater. And
that takes everything out the water.
So for baby bottles and coffee,
I use that.
But this means that for every other kind
of bath, shower, and you can use tap
water for whatever, it filters it.
It doesn't filter it to the same amount,
but for me it's quite nice knowing that
Kian's skin's getting bad-
Yeah
... after his rashes. Anyway,
two plumbers come.
The plumbers are there and they're like,
"Hey brother.
Hear you're some kind of influencer
brother."
[laughs]
I was like, "No, no, it's not like that.
I just have businesses
that work online." I gave these guys like
a 30-minute deep
dive into content creation and I said,
"What is it you do in business
that you like the most?" They said they
did bathroom renovations.
Yeah.
I said to them,
"Every single bathroom renovation you do
is a story." And they were
like, "We don't get it." And I was like,
"Okay, you have a before, you have an
after. That's a story." They're like,
"Okay." And I said, "The story is
that other
people don't care about
that story unless they can see themselves
in that story."
So similar to the car.
If we wrap a black car today into satin,
someone else out
there with a black car SUV will see this,
and the reason they'll watch the video is
they want to imagine it's their car-
Yeah
... that they do it.
The same thing with the bathroom
renovations.
I said, "Every renovation you do,
some woman out there
is going to be watching that
and thinking, 'I could do
that to my bathroom.'" Now,
99 out of 100 people will
go to someone they know,
but the one person
that checks the profile and goes,
"These people are in Sydney," will reach
out to them because they want the same
story to happen in their house.
Yeah.
So I was saying to them, "Guys." I said,
"How many have you done?" They go, "We've
done hundreds." I was like, "Well,
that's hundreds of missed opportunities to
tell
a story." And I said to them as well,
whilst they're there, I go,
"I want a copper
head shower outside my house because my
neighbor's got one and I haven't got one."
Yeah.
I said,
"We could do a story where I'm there
washing myself with a hose with my
surfboard, and then it switches
and then I'm there under a shower." The
guy's like,
"We'll come fit it next week." And I
was like,
"That story alone can then get you
more business."
Yeah.
So in content creation,
sometimes people need to realize
that they're telling
stories of before and afters,
and other people will relate to
that story.
Like when people watch Harry Potter
or they watch some kind of film,
they like to
imagine being the protagonist.
They like imagining that being them.
They overcome adversity
and whatever it is. Not quite so extreme.
But yeah, every time you do a car
and you show it off,
there's going to be a cohort
of people out there that go, "Oh,
that could be me if I just booked
him."
100%.
What we do, Declan-
True
... transformative.
We wrap cars now together.
Yeah.
We're Car Wrap Team.
[laughs]
We're gonna, what were you saying?
Mezzanine here?
Yeah, we're gonna put a mezzanine in
and we're gonna have three bays,
three wrap
bays,
and we're gonna see how this shop goes.
Quite a small detailed shop.
We'll just see how that goes,
and maybe we'll go bigger.
If you're in Sydney and we
were to hire a trainee wrap artist, would
you let a trainee wrap your car? Well,
actually we'll have Declan first.
Hmm.
We'll get you the ... Your mum's car.
We're wrapping it.
Yeah. [laughs]
No. Tell your mum.
Your mum's getting a pink car. [laughs]
Your mum's getting a pink car.
It's getting wrapped.
Are you gonna wrap the Hilux?
Did you crunch any numbers for the Hilux?
Not yet.
Let's survive this month first and then-
Yeah. [laughs]
... decide. We'll look at it. Cool.
Now we've got some cool projects coming up
in Sydney, and then we've got some
really good local jobs too.
We'll have to do a new Neutronic flavor
drop on the car. A new wrap color.
Yeah.
See, if we had three members of staff,
three wrap bays,
every time a new Neutronic
product comes out,
we could rewrap the car.
Yeah.
Or they could wrap it. We're busy.
We're gonna be busy.
All right, sick.
I think I owe BMW an apology. This
is actually quite nice in here.
The M3 Touring, I love this car.
I think this is great.
I've never been in one.
Oh, you're the one who- Let me show you.
Yeah.
This is actually quite nice, bruv. This
is actually quite nice, Declan.
It's got nice paddles on it.
They actually feel quite premium.
They're carbon fiber as well. This
or an Audi RS6.
Could be closer than I thought.
It's nice in here. Boys with toys.
These are expensive friendships.
Have I got you a bit of business? Well,
would you PPF this the same color?
If I'm gonna do it, it's gonna be satin.
It'll be to make it look like the Frozen.
So would you go satin on the existing
color or satin black?
No, if I satin,
it's gonna be the whole thing, but
if I track pack it'll be in
gloss. Track pack means just the front?
Yeah. Yeah. Just front and the sides.
Front and the sides, yeah.
Learning. We're learning.
Look at that.
Can't even put a video together without
getting some business.
I'm telling you, this
is the easiest business to get into ever.
And this is all business expense really
for the new channel.
Are you gonna put a stoot on the side?
[laughs] Just protecting an asset, right?
Will the ATO think there's a bit of
branding on it? It's not tax evasion.
It is business expense. This
is what the car's gonna look like.
This is aesthetics. It's protection.
It's an investment.
Is this gonna be a good business choice to
move
into an avenue like this?
Only you will know.
We'll discuss it in the comments.
How many days for the rest?
We've got about three days left in it,
I think,
and then we'll let it sort of cure,
dry, get all the edges right,
make it look beautiful. Drive away.
Happy days.
Sweet. Every time I get a wrap done,
there's always 300 kilometers on the clock
more than when I got you.
[laughs] Unless petrol.
[laughs]